<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Inside LINZ</title>
  <subtitle>Adventures of the Inaugural Fellows</subtitle>
  <link href="/Inside-LINZ/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://codeforaotearoa.github.io/Inside-LINZ/"/>
  <updated>2016-09-20T14:23:49.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://codeforaotearoa.github.io/Inside-LINZ/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Marcus Crane and Vaishnavi Iyer</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The World Called LINZ</title>
    <link href="http://codeforaotearoa.github.io/Inside-LINZ/2016/09/19/The-World-Called-LINZ/"/>
    <id>http://codeforaotearoa.github.io/Inside-LINZ/2016/09/19/The-World-Called-LINZ/</id>
    <published>2016-09-19T03:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-20T14:23:49.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://linz.govt.nz/" target="_blank" rel="external">Land Information New Zealand</a> or Toitū Te Whenua, popularly known as LINZ, is the government agency responsible for making regulations that govern our land.</p>
<p>LINZ is also the organisation that has pioneered the push for open data in New Zealand, which they are currently at the forefront of.</p>
<h2 id="So-who-am-I"><a href="#So-who-am-I" class="headerlink" title="So who am I?"></a>So who am I?</h2><p>Well, dear reader, I’m Vaishnavi - a software developer who along with my other developer friends - Marcus, Pete and Gabby, have joined a pilot program called <a href="http://codeforaotearoa.org" target="_blank" rel="external">Code For Aotearoa</a>. We strongly believe that the keyboard is mightier than the sword and that we are here to change the world.</p>
<h2 id="What-is-this-Code-for-Aotearoa-now"><a href="#What-is-this-Code-for-Aotearoa-now" class="headerlink" title="What is this Code for Aotearoa now?"></a>What is this Code for Aotearoa now?</h2><p>Code for Aotearoa is a pilot to open new ways through which we cam make meaningful contributions to government.</p>
<h2 id="8th-September-2016…-the-day-my-world-collided-with-these-two-other-dimensions-Code-for-Aotearoa-and-LINZ…"><a href="#8th-September-2016…-the-day-my-world-collided-with-these-two-other-dimensions-Code-for-Aotearoa-and-LINZ…" class="headerlink" title="8th September 2016… the day my world collided with these two other dimensions - Code for Aotearoa and LINZ…"></a>8th September 2016… the day my world collided with these two other dimensions - Code for Aotearoa and LINZ…</h2><p>The first week at LINZ went by really quick… I had the opportunity to meet a lot of amazing people who have a wealth of knowledge. Just meeting so many interesting people would have been a task in itself, let alone being able to get an insight into their work.</p>
<p>Like any organisation of people, there’s… a wide range of personalities. Some welcoming and others… could do with a bit of work but perhaps they’ll warm up to us in time. Each meeting has been a learning experience, that’s for sure!</p>
<h2 id="So-many-meetings-and-a-boatload-of-new-information"><a href="#So-many-meetings-and-a-boatload-of-new-information" class="headerlink" title="So many meetings and a boatload of new information,"></a>So many meetings and a boatload of new information,</h2><p>Both me and Marcus have the daunting task of assimilating the information and then start the second phase of interviews…</p>
<p>As for LINZ, I can say that they have done a great job of releasing heaps of data, which has made it challenging for us to add value to their current offerings.</p>
<p>That said, competition is what drives innovation and since that doesn’t apply to LINZ, we hope to instill a bit of friendly competition with the people we meet.</p>
<p>As for solutions, identifying the pain points of their immediate customers would definitely be a good start.</p>
<p>Until next week this has been Vai signing off…</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://linz.govt.nz/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Land Information New Zealand&lt;/a&gt; or Toitū Te Whenua, popularly known as LIN
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
